Elizabeth Stevens

Arlington Heights, II 60004 betsystevens5@gmail.com

Software Engineer seeking a *re-entry* position in **Software Development** following a family leave.

I am extremely excited to return to my previous work of designing and creating software. After completing the core course work for my B.S. in Computer Science, I worked for 5 years as a professional software developer. Over the past 20 years I have been a stay-at-home mom caring for my family. Since receiving my degree, I have continued to code for myself and for several volunteer projects. I have steadily learned new technologies through on-line courses, reading and remaining curious of all software trends. I am an eager and enthusiastic learner. I am ready to apply myself full time to an entry-level software developer position.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Java

• JavaScript

PHP

• CSS

HTML

• MySQL

• C

• Unix/Linux

Bash Shell

5+ YEARS PROFESSIONAL SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

January 2001 – present Stay at home mom, demonstrating leadership and time

management skills, and a tireless work ethic.

September 2000 – January 2001 Technical Documentation, Syclo LLC, Hoffman Estates, Illinois

Contract Work

November 1998 – September 2000 Full-time family leave to care for toddler and new born

April 1994 – November 1998 Software Developer, Accuvoice Inc., Northbrook, Illinois

C, SQL, PL/SQL, bash shell, Oracle, Unix

All phases of the software development lifecycle with focus in

design and development.

October 1993 – April 1994 Software Developer, AGT, Columbus, Ohio

C, SQL, PL/SQL, bash shell, Oracle, Unix

Software development - mainly modifications to existing code.

Proven Abilities & Characteristics

- Strong Organizational Skills
- Strong Communication Skills
- Strong Team Player
- Highly Motivated
- Detail Oriented

- Ability to Multitask and Prioritize
- Passion for Technology
- Tenacity for Solving Challenging Problems
- Strong Aptitude for Financial Analytics
- Embraces all Opportunities for Learning

FORMAL EDUCATION

2004 B.S. Computer Science, Business Minor Indiana University - Bloomington, Indiana

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Implemented a highly successful Boy Scout Plant Sale for seven years, involvement ongoing.

- Designed and implemented a data entry system for the sale using a LAMP set-up in the cloud on an AWS virtual machine image.
- 2015 Redesigned and upgraded the High School Band's GoDaddy web site.

CONTINUED EDUCATION

- 2018 JavaScript Essential Training Lynda.com
- 2017 Creating a Responsive Web Design Lynda.com
- 2016 Object Oriented Programming in Java Coursera University of California
- 2015 Analysis of Algorithms with Programming in Java Coursera Princeton University
- 2015 Programming in Python Coursera Rice University

Board & Volunteer positions:

2014-2015	BGIA, High School Band Organization – Fundraising & Website
2008-2015	Boy Scouts – Fundraising, Plant Sale Chair
2005-2008	Cub Scouts – Committee Chair
2004-2006	Cub Scouts – Advancement Chair
2003-2004	PTA – Legislative Chair

LIFE LONG LEARNER

I am a life long learner and have stayed abreast of new technologies due to my interests in software, business, math and science. Along with software development I am particularly interested in data science, statistics and discrete mathematics.

Personal Characteristics

I enjoy designing, creating and building. I consistently strive to deliver quality products whether it is for computer software, school organizations, scouting events, fundraisers, halloween costumes or party food. I equally enjoy improving upon existing systems and products, whether they are mine or someone else's.